Ariel, this is Sara.
How many voice mails do I have to leave
before you call back?
Damn it, I need to talk to you.
Please, call me ba...
Ethan, listen.
Our circulation is up 6 percent.
You want to know why?
Because I live on five hours' sleep and the
only man in my life is Mr. Coffee, okay?
Hang on. Hi. Thanks.
If advertisers don't like the new rates...
then find a magazine
with bigger words and smaller pictures.
Ethan, I got to go.
I will talk to you about it later.
I am so glad you're here, Ariel.
Pearl Jam's manager just called,
they want to reschedule the interview.
That's exactly why
I don't date musicians.
Oh, and also, one more thing,
your sister called last night.
I will shoot her an e-mail
when I get a chance.
Not bad.
Have the article on my desk by 3:00.
Paul was hoping that you could make it
to the shoot later.
Really, now?
He says he wants creative input, but I think
he's looking for an excuse to see you.
I thought all photographers were gay.
Oh, well, for a gay guy,
he sure likes to stare at your ass.
Having fun?
It's a tough job,
but someone's got to do it.
- Hey. Oh.
- Hey. Oh, come on.
When faced with natural beauty,
I just can't help myself.
- Does this rap ever work with women?
- It's not a rap if it's true.
- Right.
Huh.
The Middle Ages were
a breeding ground for superstition.
Visions of departed souls,
angels and devils were common.
While the Church grew
in power and influence...
another movement began to spread
across the Continent like a dark plague:
The cult of the demon Baphomet.
The Inquisition forced the cult members
to go underground.
And that's when the Baphomet idol
disappeared.
The statue has been lost for centuries.
I have been trying to find it for decades.
My search has taken me all across Europe
and deep into the Old World's bloody past.
Man has always been drawn
to the dark side, which is good for me.
Otherwise, I wouldn't be selling
any books today.
And after that shameless plug,
I thank you.
Thank you.
Woo. Yeah. Right on.
Guys, guys, please, one at a time, really.
The book's not even that good.
Ho, ho, ho.
So, what does a girl have to do
to get her book signed?
Hold it.
Oh. Okay.
Okay.
Dr. Hammer.
- Oh. Heh, heh, heh.
- Dude, can you knock?
Someone's working hard on their Ph. D.
Fuck you, Kyle.
Cut it out, the both of you.
What is it, Kyle?
Oh, shit, sorry.
I thought this couldn't wait.
It's about Sara Wolfe.
Sorry, sorry.
No, no, it's okay.
Mom, this isn't a good time.
Mom?
Mom, what's wrong?
Hey.
Thanks.
The neighbors found her
early this morning.
The cops say she shot herself.
I am... I am so sorry.
You know, my sister needed to talk me,
and all I could think about was work.
If there's anything you need, just...
Are you free tonight?
I really appreciate you coming along.
I don't think I could do this by myself.
Yeah, I am glad to help out.
You sure you want to do this?
You know, Sara was trying to reach me
before she died.
I need to know why.
Holy shit.
Isn't this the house where
all those people died a few years ago?
Yeah. My sister was one of the few
that made it out alive.
I remember seeing it on the news.
Steven Price flipped out,
went on a killing spree.
Not what happened,
according to my sister.
- What do you mean?
- Sara believed the house was haunted.
That ghosts killed Price's party guests.
Well, that's insane.
That's why we stopped talking.
Sara?
You must help them.
Hey, what...? What is it?
Are you okay? What's wrong?
- You didn't see that?
- See what?
God, I think I am losing my mind.
That's exactly
what your sister used to say.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
I am here for the same reason you are.
I want to know
what really happened to your sister.
My name is Dr. Richard Hammer.
I teach archaeology
and medieval history at Forman College.
Your sister contacted me two weeks ago.
Contacted you about what?
Sara had gotten hold of
Dr. Vannacutt's journal.
Okay, I am sorry,
I still don't understand.
I have been trying to find the
Baphomet idol... Wait, the what?
It's a statue
of incredible archaeological value.
I have been trying to find it
for years now.
According to Dr. Vannacutt's journal,
the statue is here in Los Angeles...
inside the hill house.
Your sister was going to come back
to the house and help me find it.
Now I know you're full of shit.
Sara would never go back to that house,
she was terrified of it.
We're out of here.
You're right.
Sara was afraid of the house.
But she was ready to face her demons.
Hey, back off.
Ariel, do you know
what happened to Vannacutt's journal?
How should I know?
Let go of the damn door.
- Sara thought she was being followed.
- What are you talking about?
The idol is worth millions
to the right collector.
There could be other
interested parties out there.
What are you saying, someone went after
my sister for this journal?
All I am saying is, be careful.
Thank you.
For being you.
Hey, it's...
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Night.
What the?
Sara, what were you up to?
The journal.
Paul?
- You're never going to believe this.
Ariel, don't....
Hey.
Let him go.
- Leave her the fuck alone.
- Yeah?
What are you going to do?
You going to take a picture of me while
I put a fucking bullet in your head? Hmm?
Sit down.
Ah, yes. Your little magazine.
Wow.
You should be proud.
Oh.
What?
I swear, I only read it for the articles.
- Who the hell are you people?
- Well, let's just say we're art lovers.
- You're after the Baphomet statue.
- Bingo, give that girl a prize.
- You're the bastard who killed my sister.
- That's not what the police say. Not at all.
But I must admit, the suicide note?
Oh.
That was inspired.
I think Helmut Newton here
has got the hots for his boss.
You're going to pay
for what you did to my sister.
Oh, let's not get abusive,
now, sweetheart.
I urged your sister to cooperate.
She chose to be a bitch.
I highly suggest
you don't follow her example.
Let's go, kids.
Get up. Come on.
Come on.
- Get up. Come on.
What are you doing?
Looks like the two of you
are going to be joining us on a trip.
Why? You got what you came for.
I can't have you running
to the cops.
I seriously doubt the authorities would
fall for yet another suicide in the family.
Do you?
Pretty creepy, isn't it?
You know, they say that the souls
of the people who died here...
apparently still haunt the house.
They also say that people who
believe in ghosts should be on Prozac.
I am sorry, I wasn't listening,
I was looking at your breasts.
Kyle.
So why is it that this can't wait
till tomorrow, again?
The journal is missing
and I am not taking any chances.
If the Baphomet idol really is here...
you think I am going to let someone
else walk away with the prize?
It will be okay.
You make a beautiful couple.
Wow.
This place is gnarly.
Ironic, isn't it?
Years of searching the globe...
when I should have been looking
in my own backyard.
Uh, question.
What?
How does a medieval artifact end up
in Vannacutt's loony bin, anyway?
Vannacutt was a big art collector,
traveled all across the world.
He believed art could be therapeutic.
You know, soothe disturbed minds.
Heh. Isn't that the way you feel about
your action-figure collection, Kyle?
Ow. Not funny.
Lovely, isn't it?
Who needs the journal when
you got the best gear money can buy?
Now, listen up, class.
GPR, ground-penetrating radar.
Emits an electromagnetic signal.
Allows you to locate anomalies
or hollow spaces.
Huh.
Oh, my God, you're right. It so works.
All right. You're coming with us.
- Why?
- Well, your sister was obsessed...
with the house. Um...
I figure she told you a thing or two
that could prove useful.
Why would I help the man
that killed my sister?
Because you don't want me to become
the man who killed your boyfriend.
Sam's going to stay here with pretty boy.
Make sure you don't get any funny ideas,
because Samuel will kill you.
Right, Samuel?
Huh?
Oh, yeah, I will kill you.
See?
I will be okay.
All right.
Let's crash this party.
Get off. Get off me.
What's going on?
Looks like we have got visitors.
Ariel. What are you doing here?
Desmond.
Oh, shit.
Ariel, why did you
bring these people here?
Mmm... She didn't.
We just kind of let ourselves in.
Guess what I found.
What's going on? You know this asshole?
Desmond Niles,
a former student of mine.
"Asshole." That's not very friendly, Ariel.
And actually, Richie boy...
nowadays, I am not your student...
I am your competition.
Who's your buyer? Maxwell? Rupert?
A gentleman never kisses and tells.
This statue belongs in a museum,
not in the hands of some private collector.
I got 5 million reasons that say otherwise.
How did you find out about the journal?
This is where it gets ugly.
Why am I not surprised?
Michelle, what the hell's going on here?
It's really simple, honey.
I am about to graduate.
Am I going to teach a bunch of freshmen...
the difference between Homo erectus...
and Homo sapiens?
Or am I going to sit on a yacht
and work on my tan?
How can you be saying these things?
What did he do to you?
- Everything?
- Yeah.
That you were too busy to do.
Jesus. I don't know you.
You going to leave
without giving me a goodbye kiss?
Did you hear that?
The house is going into lockdown.
What are you talking about?
Vannacutt installed a mechanism
that can seal up the whole asylum.
Made it impossible for patients to escape.
That's how Price's guests
got trapped in the first place.
Good old Vannacutt.
The field of medicine
wouldn't be the same without him.
If this place goes into lockdown,
we will be trapped.
Well, that's why our first stop's
going to be the master control room.
Let the tour begin.
Mansions with their own mental wards.
Only in fucking L.A.
How twisted.
Having a hard time deciphering
Vannacutt's handwriting?
You should let me take a look.
Richard.
Oh.
Does anyone else want to take a look?
No? Okay. I didn't think so.
As far as I can tell,
Vannacutt hid the idol...
in a secret chamber
deep in the basement.
So why don't we all take a corridor...
and cover as much ground as possible?
Whoa, time-out.
Desmond, right?
You're not seriously suggesting
that we all split up...
in a haunted house, are you?
Fucking shitty water.
That's all I needed.
Knee-high in shitty water.
Thanks a lot.
Come on, mate.
You kind of look familiar to me.
Oh, my God, I have got it.
You're "Notorious" Norris Boz, right?
You were like
UFC heavyweight champ, dude.
Yeah. Ha, ha, ha.
Those were the good old days.
Heh, heh, heh.
Ow.
Yeah, good old days.
Just so you know, you fight like a girl.
Like a lady.
Oh, fuck this, mate. Come on, whatever.
This place is something else, huh?
Are you going to mope all night long now?
What could I possibly have to say to you?
Don't be such a baby. The only thing
hurting you right now is your big ego.
- How long has this been going on?
- Does it really matter?
- I can't believe you're doing this.
- You will get over it.
I loved you, Michelle.
The only thing you love, Richard, is you.
It's time I looked out for myself.
Yeah, well,
you seem to have a knack for that.
Yeah, well, I learned from the best.
Come on, baby. Where are you?
Where are you? Come on.
There's something here.
Where the fuck are you?
It's about fucking time.
Five million dead presidents,
here I fucking come.
Yo, D. Can you read me?
I think I got...
God, no.
God, no, no, no.
So your sister,
she really believed in ghosts, huh?
Leave me the fuck alone.
Call me crazy if you like...
but I only believe in what I can see...
and touch...
and taste.
You really don't like me now, do you?
Kinky shit.
What the hell?
Stay right where you are.
Don't fucking move.
Who the hell are you?
How did you get in here?
Holy shit.
Shit.
Desmond to Norris, do you copy?
Norris, answer me, goddamn it.
Desmond, I am here, mate.
What's going on? Come on.
- Hello?
Look, I need you to head back.
Meet me in the main salon.
I heard gunshots.
Warren, Harue, can you read me?
Do you copy?
What's going on?
Shit.
Do it, Ariel.
Open the door.
What the fuck happened?
Exactly what my sister said
would happen.
You okay?
How did she get that thing on by herself?
Samuel, we need you in the house.
Is everything okay in there?
Come into the house.
Shit. Okay, looks like we're going to
get wet, pretty boy. Let's go.
All this time, I thought she was crazy.
My sister was telling the truth
about this place.
- We're not alone in this house.
- What the hell is she babbling about?
I saw a man.
He was a patient here.
I think he led an uprising
the night that the hospital burnt down.
I think he was trying
to stop Dr. Vannacutt.
Okay, it's official. You're fucking crazy.
I have heard enough of this.
Enough. Let's go back upstairs
and find the others.
- Come on, move.
Let's go.
Desmond, mate.
We're back upstairs in the main area.
Desmond?
Hey.
The fuck was that?
- Ha, ha, ha.
- Whew. Huh.
It's nothing, mate.
This place is ass-fucking my mind.
Desmond, mate. Come in, where are you?
What the...?
Ow.
Fuck.
- Oh, my God.
Hey, mate, help me out.
Get them off me.
Fucking help me, mate, come on.
- Fuck.
Help.
Help me, man. Ah.
Holy shit.
Kyle?
Aah.
Shit.
Where the hell's Norris?
I think you're standing in Norris.
Norris, where the hell are you?
Warren, Harue. Goddamn it,
will one of you guys answer me?
Kyle, what happened here?
Oh, God.
Hey.
It's true, isn't it?
The house, it's...
Fuck.
What the fuck is going on?
You took care
of the lockdown mechanism.
What the hell are you doing in here?
The fuck are you doing here?
I told you to stay in the car.
Paul?
Paul. Paul.
No.
No. No. No.
Ariel.
Fuck you too.
- Hey, back off. You told me to come in.
I did no such thing.
I spoke to you on the two-way.
- Whoever you talked to, it wasn't me.
It was the house.
Ariel.
- Oh, thank God. Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Hey.
How did you get back in here?
The house wanted me to return.
So what?
You just walked straight back in.
- You're crazy.
- I don't leave my friends behind.
Yeah. How touching.
Wait, the house wanted you to...?
I don't... The house?
Look, according to my sister,
last time it was seeking revenge.
Going after the descendants
of the orderlies that escaped the fire.
But this time is different.
What's wrong with you?
There's no such thing as ghosts.
Dude. I just saw one of your guerrillas
ripped to little pieces.
- This shit is as real as it fucking gets.
- Somebody's playing a game with us.
Don't you get it? All right?
I bet it's Warren, all right?
Greedy little fucker.
He's probably playing a trick on us, right?
I mean... Fucking prick.
And I bet the whole lot is in on it.
All right?
You're so in denial, man.
You know what? He's right.
Your team has nothing to do with this.
My guess is they're all dead.
Where's Samuel?
Wasn't he right behind me?
Then there were six.
Samuel, where the fuck are you?
Oh, fuck. What the fuck?
You crazy bitch. Help.
You crazy fuck.
Let me out of the fucking chair.
Samuel, answer, and right fucking now.
Who is it?
Hello?
This isn't real.
Or is it?
What are you doing?
Stop it. Stop...
Wait. Wait. Wait.
Listen. Is there any way we can reverse
the lockdown mechanism?
I doubt the house is going
to let us do that.
You know what?
Fuck this. I am out of here.
Nobody goes anywhere until we get
what we came for, understand?
Really? Little girls with big guns
only look good in movies, kid.
Shut the fuck up.
You're not a killer, Ariel.
Really? Are you sure?
You're the scumbag who killed my sister.
Let's just relax and put those guns down
before someone gets hurt.
There's a $5 million check out there with
my name on it, and I intend to cash it.
Really? Five million dollars?
Is that how much
my sister's life was worth?
Our only chance of getting out of here
in one piece is if we work together.
Too bad I am not a team player,
Richie boy.
- Say bye-bye.
Desmond, watch out.
Fuck.
Shit. Fuck. Fuck.
I'd be careful with that if I was you.
That was for Sara.
Keep an eye on them, will you?
No problem.
According to these blueprints...
the asylum was connected
to a water-supply system in 1897.
There's a sewer tunnel
that runs underneath the house.
Go on.
Well, the shower area is located
above the drainage system.
I bet we could find a sewer grate
down there that we could access.
Hey, that could work.
All right. So the quickest way
to the shower area...
is through the hydrotherapy room,
down the east corridor...
and up another hallway. Here.
Yeah, that looks easy enough.
The house is going to do
everything in its power to stop us.
Of course.
Because that's what houses do.
I just had a thought.
I remember Vannacutt
mentioning in his journal...
that the Baphomet idol
was guarded by the dead.
I figured he was speaking metaphorically,
now I am not so sure, because guess what.
- There's a crematorium in the basement.
Wait a minute.
Why the hell would there be
a crematorium inside a mental asylum?
I know during the tuberculosis epidemic,
the institute took in regular patients.
Presumably,
some were cremated in the hospital...
in order to minimize further infection.
So if we find the crematorium,
we find the idol.
I don't give a damn about the idol.
I care about getting out alive.
What about you, Richard?
Is that all you care about?
Are you really going to let
this opportunity pass you by?
We're talking about the Baphomet idol.
The prize you have been chasing
all these years.
Personally, I don't think you can.
I know you too well.
It's your life's work.
If you guys want to get yourselves killed
chasing after this stupid thing, be my guest.
Paul and I are getting out.
So, what's it going to be?
I am coming with you.
Vannacutt was known for being a brilliant
physician and great humanitarian.
Nominated for the Nobel Prize in the '20s.
But somehow, this great man went from
saving people to butchering them.
Why?
Um, I have a theory. Maybe he was nuts?
The Church believed the statue
possessed an evil influence over men.
Those who wanted its power
were susceptible.
Are you saying this statue corrupted
Vannacutt and his staff somehow?
Crazy, huh?
What the fuck did they use this for?
Hydro-pool therapy.
Hydro-what?
One of Vannacutt's special
contributions to modern medicine.
Expose a patient to a pool
filled with freezing water.
Replace internal pain with external pain
and they will cancel each other out.
Nice. Wonder why it didn't catch on.
Shut up.
What's going on?
Richard.
No, you shut up.
I got the map, Desmond. Let's go.
Ariel.
Kyle. Kyle. Please, Kyle.
Ariel. Hold on.
Kyle.
Guys, you got to find a way
to get us out of here.
Ariel.
Oh, God. Please, wait.
- I can't. I can't.
I can't reach you.
Aah. Holy shit.
I will kill you, you bitch.
Kyle.
Help me.
Hurry.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Okay.
You have no idea where we are, do you?
I would if you kept your trap shut
for one second, sweetheart.
How hard can it be
to find a goddamn crematorium?
It's on the map, isn't it?
I will get us there.
You mean
if the house doesn't get us first.
- Getting a little superstitious?
- No, of course not.
But why aren't your men answering you?
Look, I already told you.
They're probably after the idol themselves.
Maybe, but why not find the idol
and then turn on us?
It doesn't make any sense.
That crazy bitch is finally getting to you.
Or maybe...
Or maybe you're part of this.
Why are you looking at me like that?
You're trying to tell me
that you suddenly believe in ghosts?
What are you doing?
That's it, isn't it?
You're looking to play me
like you did Richard.
- Desmond, don't be ridiculous.
- How do I know you're not with them?
Desmond, put the gun away.
Betray one man,
how soon before the next?
Jesus Christ, Desmond, it's me.
Put the goddamn gun down.
- Get them on the radio.
- What?
Put whoever's behind this
on the goddamn radio.
You're not making any sense,
you're crazy. Put them on.
- There's nothing going on.
- Put them on the radio.
Oh, my God.
Michelle.
Jesus.
Why didn't those things
come after us?
I don't know.
But I think some of these souls
are reliving their final moments...
over and over again.
Trapped in the place where they died.
Thanks for saving my life back there.
Both of you.
Are you okay?
I convinced Kyle to come along for this.
The kid's dead because of me.
Don't say that.
You didn't kill Kyle. Desmond did.
You think you can get us out of here
without the blueprints?
I will give it my best shot.
Goddamn it, Desmond.
Michelle.
Oh, my God.
This must be it.
Hey, I found something.
Okay, help me lift it.
- I don't think that's going to happen.
- It has to. It's the only way out.
Damn it.
Destroy the statue.
Ariel, what is it? You okay?
We can't leave.
What?
- I know how to make it stop.
- What are you talking about?
The spirits here. They want to be
at peace, but the evil won't let them.
You're talking about Vannacutt.
Vannacutt is just a servant.
Of Baphomet.
That's why my sister was trying to
help you find the statue.
The idol is the heart of this place.
You destroy it,
you break Baphomet's hold.
It's the only way to defeat the house.
What do we do now?
One of these furnaces
has a chamber that leads to the idol.
You're saying we have to crawl
into one of these things?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's the only way.
This is it.
This is the entrance.
You ready to do this?
Ready as I will ever be.
Listen, um...
- If we don't make it out of here, I...
- We will make it.
If we don't make it,
I just want you to know that...
What?
That, uh...
That you make a lot of typos
for the editor of a magazine?
It's okay.
Like half your staff know by now.
All right, you two,
I am getting all choked up over here.
Let's do this.
I think we're almost there.
Jesus. What the hell is this stuff?
It seems to be organic.
The heart of the house.
It's remarkable.
What are you doing?
Richard, what are you doing?
Richard, step aside.
Richard.
I have to destroy it. I said, move.
Hey, Richard. Hey.
Jesus, hey.
Hey.
Richard.
- Step aside.
- Uh-huh. Yeah.
Yeah.
It was calling me.
I could feel its power.
Damn it.
Shit, you didn't even scratch it.
If we can't destroy the statue,
then maybe there's another way.
Such as?
Well...
as long as the Baphomet idol
is in the house...
the souls are trapped here, right?
So, what happens if we remove it?
How do you plan on doing that?
In case you hadn't noticed,
we can't get out.
Yeah. We noticed.
The sewer tunnel.
The statue is small enough
to fit through the grate.
I don't know about this.
Well, do you have
any better suggestions?
I say it's worth a shot.
All right.
I don't think we're alone anymore.
Let's go.
Going somewhere?
We don't have time for this.
Yeah, well, you better make time.
Is that it?
Well, Richard, I knew
you wouldn't leave without it.
All right, come on. Give it to me.
Come on.
Give it to me, now.
What?
No. No.
No. No. No.
Run.
Oh, shit.
Paul.
Keep going. Get the idol out of here,
I will be all right.
Go.
No.
What are you doing?
I have been looking for this statue
for 20 years.
It belongs to me.
Richard, if we don't do this,
we're all going to die.
Richard, get off me.
You can fight it.
Fight it.
Ariel.
Ariel, I am okay.
Ariel, wake up.
Ariel, the idol.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
No.
No. No.
- Paul.
- Ariel.
Come on.
Hey.
What is it? You okay?
Baphomet's evil has been trapped
in that house for over 50 years.
We set it free.
You're...
You're saying the house...
The house wanted us to succeed?
I don't know.
Let's go home.
What is it?
I don't know.
I think it might be worth something.